61. Easter Island If you wanted to get as far away from other
people as you possibly could, Easter Island would be a good place to go. It's about 2,000
kilometers from its nearest neighbors out in the southern Pacific Ocean. Easter Island
is a small triangle about 3,500 kilometers west of Chile. Easter Island is a special
territory of Chile. It was discovered by a Dutch explorer in 1722, but it had been
inhabited for about a thousand years before that. Scientists think that the first settlers
on Easter Island came from the Marquesas Islands more than 3,000 kilometers away. Imagine making
that journey in a small canoe. Easter Island is famous for its huge stone statues called
moai that line many of the island's coasts. The moai are statues of men with huge heads
and stern faces. Archaeologists believe the statues represent ancestors. Easter Islanders
put the statues up to allow the ancestors to continue to watch over their lands. The
moai were made between AD 1100 and AD 1688. Amazingly, Easter Islanders used only hand
tools like chisels to make them. Some of these statues weighed more than 80 tons. Archaeologists
aren't sure how these statues were moved. It must have taken many people working together
to transport them. In addition to the moai, Easter Island has other stone carvings, stone
buildings and wood carvings. This unique culture developed its own written language, though
most of it has been lost. Easter Island has suffered many tragedies, including war, hunger,
slavery, disease and environmental disasters. It can be difficult to be so far from the
rest of the world. But Easter Islanders seem hardy and strong like their statues. They
are preserving their ancient culture while connecting more and more with the outside
world.